(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-28T04:48:45.728098",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
人目角に立たないように
So I won't stand out,
愛せないように
So I won't show love,
期待しないように大切しないように
So I won't hope for anything.
ことあるごと角が立たないように
So things won't get awkward.
気取らないように目立たないように
So I won't pry, so I won't stand out.
誰一人傷付けぬように
So no one will get hurt at all.
虐めぬように殺さぬように
So I won't bully or kill anyone.
ことあるごと偽善がバレないように
So my hypocrisy won't show.
威張らないように
So I won't look arrogant.
軽いジョークやリップサービスも忘れないように
Not forgetting light jokes and lip service.
どんな時も笑って愛嬌振りまくように
Smiling at all times to put on a charming front.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter Choco Decoration.
兎角言わずにたんと言召し上がれ
Don't even speak and just eat it up.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter Choco Decoration.
食わず嫌いはちゃんと直さなきゃね
Fix your bad habits, you picky eater.
頭空っぽその後に残る心が本物なら
If an empty mind leaves a real heart behind,
きっと君だって同じ事
I'm sure you're just the same.
「ところで一つ伺いますが
"By the way, let me ask you one thing..."
先日何処かで？…やっぱりいいや」
"Where was it the other day... actually, never mind."
無駄に自我を晒さぬように
So I won't expose my ego needlessly.
話さないように分からないように
So I won't speak, so I won't be understood.
人を過度に信じないように
Never trusting people too much,
愛さないように期待しないように
never loving or expecting too much.
かと言って角が立たないように
Yet making sure not to cause friction,
気取らないように目立たないように
trying not to act stuck-up or stand out.
誰一人傷付けないように
Making sure not to hurt a single soul,
虐めないように殺さないように
not bullying or killing anyone.
かと言って偽善がバレないように
Yet making sure my hypocrisy isn't exposed,
威張らないように
not acting arrogant.
軽いジョークやリップサービスも忘れないように
Not forgetting light jokes and lip service either,
どんな時も笑って愛嬌振りまくように
smiling and acting charming at all times.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration!
兎角言わずにたんと召し上がれ
Without saying a word, eat your fill.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration!
食わず嫌いはきちん直さなくちゃ
You've got to fix your picky habits.
頭空っぽその後に残る心が本物なら
If the heart left behind in that empty head is real,
きっと君だって同じ事
I'm sure you're the exact same way.
「ところで一つ伺いますが 先日何処かで?…やっぱりいいや」
"By the way, may I ask something? The other day somewhere...? Actually, never mind."
無駄に自我を晒さぬように
Not exposing my ego needlessly,
話さぬように分からないように
not speaking so I won't be understood.
でも絶対口を閉じさぬように
Yet making sure never to seal my mouth shut,
笑わすより笑われるように
being laughed at rather than making others laugh.
人をちゃんと敬うように
Respecting people properly,
崇めるように讃えるように
adoring and praising them,
でも決して嫌味にならないように
but never coming across as insincere.
諂わないように
Not sucking up,
集団参加の終身刑
a life sentence of group participation.
またへーこらへーこら言っちゃって
Bowing and scraping all over again,
「あれっ、前髪ちょーぜつざいきょーじゃん！」
"Hey, your bangs are super awesome!"
とかどーでもいーのに言っちゃって
blurting out things that don't even matter.
毎朝毎晩もう限界
Every morning and night, I'm at my limit.
宗教的社会の集団リンチ
A group lynching in a religious society,
でも決して発狂しないように
yet making sure not to go crazy.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration!
時に孤独な愛は君を汚す
Sometimes lonesome love taints you.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration!
立つ鳥跡濁して糞のアート
Leaving dirty traces like a bird flying away.
初めはあんな大層な大言壮語を並べたが
At first I made such grand and boastful claims,
嫌々も好きの内
but even reluctant things grow on you.
「いやはやすけしき今日が初めてで こんなとはね 君センスあるよ」
"Good grief, since it's your first time today... you've got good taste!"
恋する季節にビターチョコデコレーション
In the season of love, bitter choco decoration!
恋する気持ちでビターチョコデコレーション
With feelings of love, bitter choco decoration!
F.U.C.K.Y.O.U
F.U.C.K. Y.O.U.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration!
皆が望む理想に憧れて
Yearning for the ideal everyone desires,
私自身と全ておさらい
reviewing myself and everything else.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration!
夢も顔も捨てて地獄送りだ
Throwing away my dreams and face to hell.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration!
やっと大人になったよママ
I've finally grown up, Mama.
明日何が起きたってこの先も地獄は続くどこまでも
No matter what happens tomorrow, hell continues forever.
だからずっと今だけを今度どころか気まぐれのままで一緒に絡まずやっていこうぜ
So let's just live in the moment on a whim without entangling.
ああ思い出したあの日のあのときのきまじめさを
Ah, I remembered the seriousness of those days.
やっぱりいいや
Actually, never mind.
サイコロ
Dice.
五が出た
Rolled a 5.
何これ？
What's this?
椅子？
A chair?
アップダウンは世の常
Ups and downs are common in this world,
クズ引いたって動かない
even if I draw a bad hand, I won't budge.
肝心なのは strong な mind
What's essential is a strong mind,
出し抜いて survive
outsmarting them to survive.
行き着く先は heaven or hell
Where we're heading is heaven or hell,
この世界のルール
the rules of this world.
たった一つ 勝者こそが 正義
There is only one: the winner is right.
女は度胸
A woman's got grit.
焦れさせるアイツを
Making those guys impatient,
やれることなんだってやる
I'll do whatever it takes.
あたしは賭け狂いのクイーン
I'm the queen of gambling madness.
お見通し それ you doubt me
I see right through you, you doubt me.
読み切って レッツ showdown
Read through it, let's showdown.
Deal with the devil
見透かして あたしのものにする
See through it and make it mine,
あなたの髪の一本まで全部
down to every single strand of your hair.
a million dollars i'd say raise
震えてるわよ坊や
You're trembling, boy.
降ろさせはしないわ
I won't let you back down.
Deal with the devil
Uhnn 興奮
Ah, what excitement!
たまらないわスリル
This thrill is irresistible.
誰にも触らせないこの money
No one's touching this money.
a million dollars i'd say raise
さあ com'on 覚悟きめて
Come on, make up your mind.
震え高ぶる my heart
My heart trembles and races.
欲しがるようじゃねまだベイビー
You're still just a baby if you only wish for it.
誰にも負けない感じさせて love me honey
Make me feel invincible, love me honey.
あなた内緒だわ
It's a secret to you,
ほら見せてあげる秘め事甘いの
look, I'll show you, secrets are sweet.
仕掛けて罠に嵌めるわ
Setting a trap to catch you,
油断誘うの
luring your carelessness.
思考を止めればジ・エンド
If you stop thinking, it's the end.
何も知らないような表情で堕とすわあなたを
With a clueless look, I'll bring you down.
虚勢でしょそれ you doubt me
That's just a bluff, you doubt me.
読み切って レッツ showdown
Read through it, let's showdown.
Deal with the devil
見逃さない
I won't miss a thing.
どんな小さなズルだってあたしの目はごまかせないわ
No matter how small the cheat, you can't fool my eyes.
a million dollars i'd say raise
勝った相手は骨まで愛し尽くしてあげる
I'll love my defeated opponent down to the bones.
狙った獲物は逃がさない
I won't let my target escape.
唇濡らせて頂くわ my babe
I'll moisten my lips before taking you, my babe.
ダイヤのジャックで手が揃うわ
With the jack of diamonds, my hand is complete.
笑みを殺し待つだけ
Just hiding my smile and waiting.
あたしのポーカーフェイスは it's perfect
My poker face is perfect.
一分の隙も見せたりしないわ
I won't show a single opening.
視線感じてるわ
I can feel your gaze.
お望みは最後まで見届ればいいじゃない
Why not watch my desire through to the end?
負けるのが怖い？ you're easy game
Afraid to lose? You're easy game.
読み切って レッツ showdown
Read through it, let's showdown.
Deal with the devil
見透かしてあたしのものにする
See through it and make it mine,
あなたの髪の一本まで全部
down to every single strand of your hair.
a million dollars i'd say raise
離れ離れの街を繋ぐ列車は行っちまったね
It seems the train connecting the far-off cities has already left
失くした言葉を知らないなら ポケットで握りしめて
If I don't know the words I lost, I'll grasp them tight in my pocket
あがいた息を捨てて延びる今日は眠って誤魔化し得
I breathe out my struggle and fake my way through today's sleep
失くした言葉を知らないなら 各駅停車に乗り込んで
If I don't know the words I lost, I'll hop on a local train
夕方と退屈なお誘いを断って
Rejecting the evening and invitations to boredom
一人きり 路地裏は決して急がないで
All alone, never rushing through the back alleys
ほら 横断歩道も待っててと言っている
Look, the crosswalk is also telling me to wait
見張る街角があなたを引き留めている
The watchful street corners are holding you back
塞がる両手があなたを引き留めている
My occupied hands are holding you back
あがいた夢を捨てて揺れる今日は眠って誤魔化し得
I throw away my struggling dreams and fake my way through today's swaying sleep
失くした言葉を知らないなら 各駅停車に乗り込んで
If I don't know the words I lost, I'll take a ride on the local train
夕方の駅のホームはひどく混み合って
The evening station platform is terribly crowded
一人占めできるまで休憩して欲しくって
I wanted it to give me a break until I could have it all to myself
また 集団下校があなたを急かしている
Again, a group returning from school is rushing you along
ほら 自動改札は待っててと言っている
Look, the automatic ticket gate is telling you to wait
塞がる両手があなたを引き留めている
My occupied hands are holding you back
あがいた夢を捨てて揺れる今日は眠って誤魔化し得
I throw away my struggling dreams and fake my way through today's swaying sleep
失くした言葉を知らないなら 各駅停車に乗り込んで
If I don't know the words I lost, I'll take a ride on the local train
離れた街と街を繋ぐ列車は 呼んだ風に飛ばされないでいてくれ
The train that connects the distant towns, please don't let it be blown away by the summoned wind
失くした言葉はそのままでいいよ
The words I lost, it's fine if you just leave them as they are
揺れる列車に身を任せてほしいから
Because I want you to entrust yourself to the swaying train
離れ離れの街を
The far-off cities...
離れ離れの街を繋ぐ列車は行っちまったね
It seems the train connecting the far-off cities has already left
失くした言葉を知らないなら ポケットで握りしめて
If I don't know the words I lost, I'll grasp them tight in my pocket
あがいた息を捨てて延びる今日は眠って誤魔化し得
I breathe out my struggle and fake my way through today's sleep
失くした言葉を知らないなら 各駅停車に乗り込んで
If I don't know the words I lost, I'll hop on a local train
夕方と退屈なお誘いを断って
Rejecting the evening and invitations to boredom
負けられないわ 怖いよ いつか
I can't afford to lose, I'm scared, someday
夢見てた列車だ
It's the train I dreamed of
目を奪って 息を潜めて あなたの髪の毛縫う
Stealing my gaze, holding my breath, weaving through your hair
一本まで縫う
Stitching every single strand
ほうり込むんだ アイラブセライ 震えてるのよもう
Tossing them in, I love you, I'm already trembling
どこまで行くの 目を奪って 天国へと突き落とす
How far are you going? Stealing my gaze, plunging me straight to heaven
忘れられない 誰りも触らせない このポエム
Unforgettable, never letting anyone touch this poem
ほうり込むんだ アイラブセライ 覚悟を決めて
Tossing them in, I love you, making up my mind
はいりになるまで 隠される 気持じゃねえ
Until I become ash, it's not a feeling you can hide
まだ ベイビー 誰にも拭けない 感じさせて ロミオとジュリエット
Still, baby, make me feel it in a way no one else can, Romeo and Juliet
ふぅ... イス... 真っ黒になっちゃった。
Whew... My chair turned pitch black.
もう少し座らせてほしかった。
I wish they had let me sit a bit longer.
はい、みんな! 見えてる? 聞こえてる?
Hi everyone! Can you see me? Can you hear me?
このライブ所属の屋敷ハーフエルフ、アキロゼことアキ・ローゼンタールです。
I'm Aki Rosenthal, the half-elf resident of Hololive!
はろはろはろ、あろはー!
Hello, hello, hello, aloha!
今回のアキロゼ生誕祭2026へようこそ!
Welcome to this Aki Rosenthal Birthday Live 2026!
早速ね、なんかいろいろ行われていたんですが、一体今回のライブはどうなっちゃうのか。
Right away, various things have been happening, but what on earth is going to happen with this live?
是非最後までひっく... お見逃しなくお願いします!
Please be sure not to miss a single second until the very end!
今回のライブのハッシュタグは「#アキロゼ生誕祭2026」
The hashtag for this live is "#AkiRosenthalBirthday2026"
こちらをつけてXにたくさんポストしてね!
Please post lots about it on X with this tag!
もちろんかわいい スクショも!
Of course, cute screenshots too!
いっぱい撮って、合わせてポストしてください。
Take lots of them and post them together.
ライブが終わったときお見逃しします...
Once the live is over...
あ、チャンネル登録もよろしくね!
Oh, and please subscribe to the channel too!
おけ? ドキドキって?
Okay? Nervous?
はい、ありがとう。
Yep, thank you.
ていうか、ここどこなんだろう?
Wait a minute, where on earth is this?
あ、あんなとこにルーレットがある。
Oh, there's a roulette wheel over there.
え... 回るのかな?
Huh... Does it spin?
まっ... まった... ええ、すごい! ももっと...
Wait... It spun... Wow, amazing! Even more...
unhappy?
悩める人の子よ
If you're dealing with a lotta woes,
unlucky?
人成らざる者も
Then you got to listen very close.
be happy!
怠まず目指せよ
Keep on trying, never give up.
undead
生きてるんだし
Don't forget that you're alive.
目を逸らした過去も
The past you have been running from,
退屈な未来も
That boring future yet to come,
カウンセリング やれやれ
Still counseling you, oh my, oh my.
古今東西 ピースピース
Universal, peace, peace, yeah!
ねぇねぇねぇねぇ
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
なんとかどうして
somehow feeling like
戦ってるような
there's a fight within and
そんな気がするの
it's been going on so long,
触れられない
I don't feel it
触れたいもない
(don't even wanna try),
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分と
past version of me (of me, of me, of me),
もうとっくに死んでる
and those figures of the old,
透明な 亡霊と対決
transparent ghosts over my route,
幼くて 痛い 記憶の奥
the childish and painful memories have the deepest roots.
残念？ もう居ないのに
(Saddening?) Nowhere to be seen,
あれ？ そっちが良い？ イロニね
(Say what?) Way better then? Irony.
透かされているのは 現在の自分？
They all see the me of the past when looking at me now.
ナンセンス
(Nonsense)
消えない レッテル
label I can't erase,
yes! 要は コンプレックス
(Yes) in essence, a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい
It's almost like something's possessing me,
巻き付いたまま
it is wrapping tight around
まだ 離れ ない
and won't loosen its bounds,
在りし日の 自分
the self I used to be before.
undead
死んじまいえない お前と お前の連鎖
still alive, time is a chain of your own path.
生きていることは 変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to always embrace your inner changes, on and on.
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't settle for unhappiness, don't be complacent in distress.
幸せになろうなんて なんて卑俗だ
Not even trying to seize the joy and be happy, you coward!
この世 この世は
Oh, this world, oh, this world
奇怪 奇怪 ファンタジー
is one odd, one odd fantasy.
次は 鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Who knows what is coming up next, a monster or a snake?
出会って 遭って 始まる 物語
This is a story starting after that encounter, finally
さあ 人か 化物か 閑話休題
with people or monsters and spirits.
ピースピース
Peace, peace, yeah!
past & future
Past and future,
can't change the past
past & future
Past and future,
run for the future
カットイン
(Cut-in)
何だか どうして
Somehow feeling like
未来になんとなんの
there's nothing to be looking forward to.
何の 希望もない 期待 出来ない
No hope to find, that's how I'm feeling inside.
ような気がして
There's nothing left to view,
もう随分生きている
lived long enough, nothing is new.
既視感と テンプレで食傷
No sign of anything wonderful waiting down the line.
素敵な 出来事の気配 もない 残念
(Saddening) Too much knowledge results in feeling
積んだ 経験の因果
like every myth is but another
形骸化 された 神話 と 退屈な進化
boring evolution (thrill is what I really want now).
飽き ちゃ っ た
Bored and down
慣れ ちゃ っ た
(used to frowns),
なんて 整えて いく ガイダンス
and this is the way the guidance grew, rising compliance too.
増える コンプライアンス 蓋 されて いく みたい
It's like I'm going under a lid.
吸い尽くして あれも これも どれ も
(I consumed everything) This one or that one or whichever,
同じ 味 が する
and now it all just tastes the same.
undead
死んじまいえない お前と お前の連鎖
still alive, time is a chain of your own path.
何時の 世 も 過去 も 未来 も 現在 にある ん だ
In any era, your past and your future are in this very moment.
生き ている ことを 愚直 に 果たせば
Fulfill the life you're set upon and truthfully keep moving on.
目指せ ハッピーエンド
Go for that happy ending!
undead
死んじまいえない お前 に 言って いる ん だ
still alive, I'm telling this to you, now.
幸せ を 諦め てしまう な 人 で 在 れ
So never give up on pursuing your happiness and keep being human,
ただ 苦しみ に 慣れて 耐えて いる だけ じゃ
'cause being numb to suffering, always enduring everything,
死ん で いる も 同様 尸 の アンデッド
it's almost as if you're dead, a lot of corpses undead.
unhappy ?
(Unhappy?)
悩める 人 の 子 よ
If you're dealing with a lotta woes,
unlucky ?
(Unlucky?)
人 成らざる 者 も
Then you gotta listen very close.
be happy !
(Be happy!)
弙 まず 目指せ よ
Keep on trying, never give up.
undead
(Undead, oh)
生き て いる ん だろ
Be aware that you're alive.
不幸 に 浸る も 幸せ に なる の も そう 全部 全部 お前 だ
Drowning deep in unhappiness or seizing that true happiness, it's on you, on you, it's all on you.
古今 東西 一切合切 森羅万象 ピースピース
Universal, all embracing all creations (peace, peace, yeah).
past & future
Past and future,
can't change the past
past & future
Past and future,
run for the future
人の 在る 何時も 憂い 事
Where people gather and go, you'll find all worries and woes.
生き抜け この 化物 ばかり の 物語
Oh, you gotta live on, through this tale of monsters everywhere that you can see!
教えて！ もっと あなた の 事
Teach me more about you
tell me more more more more. tell me more more more more
(tell me more, more, more, more...)
聴か せ て ！ もっと あなた の 声
Show me more of your voice
let me hear more more more. let me hear more more more
(let me hear more, more, more...)
こんな ドキドキ もう 抑え 切れ ない
This excitement, I can't hold back anymore
all i need you. oh ! all i need you
(all i need you)
友達 は 卒業 運命 の 私 見つけ て 欲しい の
Friends have graduated, I want destiny to find me.
one
勇気 を 出して
summon up the courage
two
見つめる 作戦
strategy of gazing
three
瞳 と 目 が 合って
when our eyes meet
fall
止め られ ない
unstoppable
yeah yeah yeah この 恋 この 愛 で melt melty 溶け ちまう よ
Can't stop yeah, yeah, yeah, with this love, this love, melt, melty, I'm melting.
ねえ ？ ねえ ？ ねえ ？ 気づいて " my darling "
Hey? Hey? Hey? Notice, "my darling"!
届け ！ 大好き ！
Reach out, because I love you!
アイ 愛 、 スクリ 〜 ム scream 叫び ましょ スリー厶 ！ アイスクリーム ！ ok !
Love, scream, let's scream, scream, ice cream, ok!
ルビィ ちゃん ！ 何 が 好き ？ チョコミント より も あ ・ な ・ た ♡
Ruby-chan? Chocolate mint, but I like you more!
歩夢 ちゃん ！ 何 が 好き ？ ストロベリー フレーバー より も あ ・ な ・ た ♡
Ayumu-chan? Strawberry flavour, but I like you more!
四季 ちゃん ！ 何 が 好き ？ クッキー ＆ クリーム より も あ ・ な ・ た ♡
Shiki-chan? Cookies and cream, but I like you more!
見つめる作戦
Staring strategy,
見つめた愛パーティー
the love party I gazed upon.
止められない
Can't be stopped!
この恋 この愛で メーメー 気づけちゃうよ
With this love and affection, meow-meow, you'll realize it!
メーメー 気づいてマイダーリン
Meow-meow, notice it, my darling!
メーメー 飛び出してマイダーリン
Meow-meow, jump out, my darling!
届けて 大好き
Deliver it! I love you!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's scream it out!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream!
アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Ice cream, let's scream it out!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream!
ルビィちゃん！はーい！何が好き？
Ruby-chan! Yes! What do you like?
チョコミントよりもあ・な・た
Even more than chocolate mint... it's you!
しきちゃん！はーい！何が好き？
Shiki-chan! Yes! What do you like?
ストロベリーフレーバーよりもあ・な・た
Even more than strawberry flavor... it's you!
歩夢ちゃん！はーい！何が好き？
Ayumu-chan! Yes! What do you like?
クッキー＆クリームよりもあ・な・た
Even more than cookies and cream... it's you!
みんな！はーい！何が好き？
Everyone! Yes! What do you like?
もちろん大好きアイスクリーム
Of course, I love ice cream!
止められない
Can't be stopped!
この恋 この愛で メーメー 気づけちゃうよ
With this love and affection, meow-meow, you'll realize it!
メーメー 気づいてマイダーリン
Meow-meow, notice it, my darling!
メーメー 気づいてマイダーリンだけ
Meow-meow, notice only me, my darling!
大好き アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
I love ice cream, ice cream!
叫びましょう アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Let's scream it out, ice cream, ice cream!
アイスクリーム 叫びましょう アイスクリーム
Ice cream, let's scream it out, ice cream!
アイスクリーム
Ice cream!
おねがい 見つけてマイダーリン
Please, find me, my darling!
おねがい 気づいてマイダーリン
Please, notice me, my darling!
勇気を出して
Summoning up my courage,
近づく作戦
the closing-in strategy!
手と手が触れて
Hand in hand, touching...
止められない
Can't be stopped!
この恋 この愛で メーメー 気づけちゃうよ
With this love and affection, meow-meow, you'll realize it!
メーメー 気づいてマイダーリンもう一人取ればあなた
Meow-meow, notice me, my darling, if you take one more, you're mine!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's scream it out!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream!
アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Ice cream, let's scream it out!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's scream it out!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream!
アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Ice cream, let's scream it out!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム
Ice cream, ice cream!
チョットでいいから見せてくれないか
Won't you show me, even just a little?
お前のセクシーフェロモンで オレ メロメロ
With your sexy pheromones, I'm completely infatuated!
オレ 怒れないか？
Can't I get mad?
行けない太陽！
The bad sun!
イケナイ太陽
[Title: Ikenai Taiyou]
ちょっとでいいから 見せてくれないか
Won't you show me, even just a little?
お前のセクシーフェロモンで オレメロメロ
With your sexy pheromones, I'm completely infatuated!
忘れちゃいそう でも行けないの 夢中に高鳴る鼓動止められないわ
I might forget, but I can't! My rapidly beating pulse can't be stopped!
交わす言葉の記憶と口元…
The memories of our exchanged words and your lips...
ちょっとでいいから見せてくれないか
Just for a second, won't you show me?
お前のセクシー・フェロモンでオレメロメロ
I'm falling down from your sexy pheromones.
Ah ふれちゃいそう でもイケナイの!
Ah, it looks like I'm going to touch you, but I can't!
徐々に高まる鼓動 止められないわ
Little by little, my pulse gets faster, I can't be stopped.
交わす言葉の 記憶遠く
Memories of the words that we exchanged are far off,
口元の動きに揺れ動く
trembling with the movement of my mouth.
濡れた髪を なでた そして ああ
I stroked your wet hair, and ah...
ABC 続かない そんなんじゃ ダメじゃない
ABC won't continue, that won't do at all.
だって ココロの奥は違うんじゃない?
But aren't things different inside of your heart?
「赤い糸」なんて絵空事 でも下心でさえ信じたいの
A "red thread" is a pipe dream, but I want to believe in my motives.
オレは正しい キミも正しい とにかくもう左右されないぜ
I'm right, you're right too; anyway, I won't be controlled anymore.
騙し騙され胸うずく 下手な芝居がより盛り上げる夜
Deceiving and being deceived, my heart aches; a terrible drama brings the night to a climax.
息が耳に触れた二人 ああ
Our breaths meet each other's ears, ah...
ABC 続かない そんなんじゃ ダメじゃない
ABC won't continue, that won't do at all.
だって ココロの奥は違うんじゃない?
But aren't things different inside of your heart?
オレの青春 そんなもんじゃない
My youth, there's no such thing;
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to finish it off passionately, inside of me.
きっと キミじゃなきゃヤダよ オレはイケナイ太陽
I definitely don't want to be without you, I'm the bad sun.
ABC 続かない そんなんじゃ ダメじゃない
ABC won't continue, that won't do at all.
だって ココロの奥は違うんじゃない?
But aren't things different inside of your heart?
私の青春 そんなもんじゃない
My youth, there's no such thing;
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to finish it off passionately, inside of me.
きっと キミじゃなきゃヤダよ 私イケナイ太陽
I definitely don't want to be without you, I'm the bad sun.
交わす言葉の 記憶遠く
Memories of the words that we exchanged are far off,
口元の動きに揺れ動く
trembling with the movement of my mouth.
濡れた髪を なでた そして ああ
I stroked your wet hair, and ah...
息が耳に触れた二人 ああ
Our breaths meet each other's ears, ah...
ABC 続かない そんなんじゃ ダメじゃない
ABC won't continue, that won't do at all.
だって ココロの奥は違うんじゃない?
But aren't things different inside of your heart?
オレの青春 そんなもんじゃない
My youth, there's no such thing;
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to finish it off passionately, inside of me.
きっと キミじゃなきゃヤダよ オレはイケナイ太陽
I definitely don't want to be without you, I'm the bad sun.
私の青春 そんなもんじゃない
My youth, there's no such thing;
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to finish it off passionately, inside of me.
きっと キミじゃなきゃヤダよ 私イケナイ太陽
I definitely don't want to be without you, I'm the bad sun.
オレを結ぶ赤い糸
Our threads are entangled, a red thread binds us.
すごいね!
That was amazing!
どうして来てくれた… ありがとう!
Thank you so much for coming!
ということで、お友達が来てくれたので、自己紹介をしてもらうと思います!
So, since our friends came over, we'll have them introduce themselves!
まずはプルルちゃんから!
First off, from Pururu-chan!
はーい! えへへ!
Hii! Ehehe!
天才すぎるお姉様 天使と悪魔のプルプルエンジェル!
The too-genius older sister, the angel and devil Pururu Angel!
あまきプルルでーす!
I'm Amaki Pururu!
かわいい! お誕生日おめでとう! おめでとうー!
So cute! Happy birthday! Congratulations!
今日はとっても楽しかったです! ありがとー!
Today was so much fun! Thank you!
そして続いてかるびちゃーん!
And next, Karubi-chan!
はい、鬼の国の姫様 赤身かるびでーす!
Yes, I'm Akami Karubi, princess of the oni realm!
やっきのぜ! 誕生日おめでとー!
Yakki no ze! Happy birthday!
生ライブって… お友達生ライブ初めてだからさ、マジで嬉しかったよ!
A live stream... Since it's my first time at a friend's live stream, I was genuinely so happy!
ありがとう呼んでくれて!
Thanks for inviting me!
いや、またやろうぜ! また!
Man, let's do this again! Again!
ありがとうー! すばらしい!
Thank you! That's wonderful!
そして最後にズズさーん!
And lastly, Zuzu-san!
はい! 僕のこと知らない人いると思うんで、自己紹介だけさせてください!
Yes! There are probably people who don't know me, so let me introduce myself!
雨降ってざーざー少女時代はジージー! 僕の名前はズズズズズズズズでございます!
Rain pouring down, the Girls' Generation is GG! My name is Zuzu-zuzu-zuzu-zuzu!
いや、お誕生日おめでとー!
Man, happy birthday!
疲れる、疲れるよね!
I'm exhausted, you must be exhausted!
おいおいおい！
Oi, oi, oi!
お忙しい人気者だ！
What a busy celebrity!
お忙しいな
So busy.
気をつけて
Be careful.
ありがとうね
Thank you.
もふりちゃ、ありがとー！
Mofuricha, thanks!
ああ、賑やかで楽しかった！
Ah, it was so lively and fun!
まるでこの世界で 二人だけみたいだね
It feels like we're the only two people in this world.
なんて少しだけ 夢を見てしまっただけ
Or so I thought, just dreaming for a little while.
つま先に月明かり 花束の香り
Moonlight on my toes, the scent of flowers,
指に触れる指 さよなら もう行かなくちゃ
fingertips touching. Goodbye, I must go.
何もかも忘れて 硝子の上を裸足のまま歩く
Forgetting everything, walking barefoot across the glass.
痛むごとに血が流れ落ちていく お願い
With every pain, blood drips down. I beg you,
その赤い足跡を辿って 会いにきて
follow these red footprints and come meet me.
錆びたプールに放たれていく金魚
A goldfish released into a rusty pool,
靴箱の中隠した林檎
an apple hidden in the shoe cabinet,
萎びた君の肌に残る傷跡
scars remaining on your withered skin.
犬のように泳ぎだす迷子
A lost child swimming like a stray dog.
どこにいるの？ (ここにいるよ)
Where are you? (I'm right here.)
何をしているの？ (ずっと見てるよ)
What are you doing? (I've been watching always.)
この世の間違いで満たそう 側にいてよ
Let's fill this world with mistakes. Stay by my side,
遊びに行こうよ どこにいるの？
let's go play. Where are you?
ガラスの上を裸足のまま歩く
Walking barefoot across the glass,
痛むごとに血が流れ落ちていく
with every pain, blood drips down.
お願い その赤い足跡を辿って 会いにきて
I beg you, follow these red footprints and come meet me.
まるでこの世界で 二人だけみたいだね
It feels like we're the only two people in this world.
なんて少しだけ 夢を見てしまっただけ
Or so I thought, just dreaming for a little while.
さあ、選択の時だ
Now, it's time to choose.
コイン
Coin.
このコインは
Is this coin...
あぁ
Ah...
そうか
I see.
君はそっちなんだね
You're on that side, huh.
そっち？
That side?
ここに座って
Sit over there.
えっ
Eh?
この後は君次第だよ
From here on, it's up to you.
あっ
Ah...
忘れられないのは この目のせい
What is unforgettable are these eyes,
赤く残る過ち 甘噛みの跡
The traces of mistakes and innocence left in red.
溢れ出す愛は 止め処もない
An overflow of love that cannot be stopped.
誰もいない間に 悪魔を探す
Looking for demons when no one is around.
作り笑いは この耳のせい
This fake smile is the fault of these ears.
深い壁の中 から呼びかける声
The voice calling from deep within the walls...
whisper, whisper, whisper まだ触らせない
Whisper, whisper, whisper, still not letting us touch.
この檻を抜け出して 悪魔は駆ける
The devil breaks out of this cage and runs.
鏡の前で この口のせい
In front of the mirror, because of this mouth...
伝えたい言葉さえ 噛み殺す 夜
The night where even words we want to say are bitten back and killed.
whisper, whisper, whisper まだ打ち明けない
Whisper, whisper, whisper, still not breaking through the dawn.
神様を裏切って 悪魔と過ごす
Betraying God and spending time with the demons.
曖昧に夢見ていたい
I want to keep dreaming vaguely...
あなたにそっと
Gently to you...
気付かせてあげたいだけ
I just want to make you notice.
おあなたにも おあなたにも おあなたにも
Oh, to you too, oh, to you too, oh, to you too.
消えない傷を隠したい
I want to hide my indelible wounds.
あなたにそッと
Gently to you...
悩ませてあげたいだけ
I just want to trouble you.
おあなたにも
Oh, to you too...
Oh, to you too.
悪魔を探す
Looking for demons.
作り笑いは この耳のせい
This fake smile is the fault of these ears.
深い壁の中 から呼びかける声
The voice calling from deep within the walls...
whisper, whisper, whisper まだ触らせない
Whisper, whisper, whisper, still not letting us touch.
この檻を抜け出して 悪魔は駆ける
The devil breaks out of this cage and runs.
鏡の前で この口のせい
In front of the mirror, because of this mouth...
伝えたい言葉さえ 噛み殺す 夜
The night where even words we want to say are bitten back and killed.
whisper, whisper, whisper まだ打ち明けない
Whisper, whisper, whisper, still not breaking through the dawn.
神様を裏切って 悪魔と過ごす
Betraying God and spending time with the demons.
好き嫌い常識 i don't care 吹っ飛び BANG!!!
Likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care, blow it away, BANG!!!
かかってこい majority あたしに負けはなし
Bring it on, majority, I won't lose to you.
ここまでって引かれたそのボーダー 誰のルール？
Who's rules are that border I was led to by going this far?
あの日乗り越えた weak heart 強くなったあたしが笑い飛ばしてあげる haha
The weak heart that rode past that day, I, having grown stronger, will laugh it away, haha.
言いたい事は言う やりたかった事はない 悪意にしない
I'll say what I want to say, I won't do what I didn't want to do, I mean no malice.
皆違うの当たり前だし あたしも変わらないニューノーマル時代
It's only natural everyone is different, and I am the same new normal era.
(everybody say i want to be free)
yesもnoも言えない それじゃ何も変えられない
Saying neither yes nor no won't change a thing.
(everybody say i want to live more)
叶えたい自分 肯定生きてるんだあたし
I am affirming and living the self I wanted to be.
ねえ 生きてるんだあたし
Hey, I am truly living!
歌え や 歌え 歌え 今を(声上げて)
Sing, oh sing, sing the present (raise your voice)!
生まれたその時から選んできたんだ
I've been choosing it ever since I was born.
思い出せあたしはあたしだ
Remember, I am myself!
不可能なことなど何一つない嘘じゃない
There's no such thing as the impossible, this isn't a lie.
なりたい自分に
Into the self I want to become!
好き嫌い常識 i don't care 吹っ飛び BANG!!!
Likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care, blow it away, BANG!!!
again
好き嫌い常識 i don't care 吹っ飛び BANG!!!
Likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care, blow it away, BANG!!!
フル10鳴らすこのリリックかます
This lyric makes full 10 rings sound out.
わからず挑発下向いて舌打ちからの「は？」
An uncomprehending, defiant, downward-looking "Huh?" from a tongue-click.
excuse me あたしからずば倍返しくだ
Excuse me, I'm returning it double without missing a beat.
食らえパンチライン 聞かせてがせて
Devour the punchline, let me hear it.
やってから考え あたしがついているからさ
Think after you do it, are you keeping up with me?
(everybody say i want to be free)
過去の美徳習慣全部黙らせ shout
Shout out and silence all virtues and habits of the past.
(everybody say i want to live more)
目覚め起きて wake up, wake up 生きてるんだあたし
Awaken, wake up, wake up, I am truly living!
ねえ 生きてるんだあたし
Hey, I am truly living!
生まれたその時から選んできたんだ
I've been choosing it ever since I was born.
思い出せあたしはあたしだ
Remember, I am myself!
平凡な自分を嫌
I hate my ordinary self,
なんでもない生活が嫌
I hate my nothing-special life.
胡散臭い売り人から買った
I bought a shady apple from
怪しい林檎を頬張った
a sketchy merchant and took a bite.
賢いワナビーはみんなやってる
Clever wannabes are all doing it,
一端の何者かに
becoming someone important,
生まれ変わってやり直せる
being reborn and starting over—
転生林檎
the Reincarnation Apple.
ある表現者になった
I became an artist,
全世界で賞賛された
praised across the entire world.
自分は特別で 他人は凡人で
I was special, others were ordinary,
その才能に酔いしれた
and I was intoxicated by my talent.
だが 人を愛する才能はなく
But I had no talent for loving others,
愛する仲間は去っていった
and the friends I loved drifted away.
ああ またダメでした
Ah, I failed again—
転生しよう
time to reincarnate.
ある発明家になった
I became an inventor,
世紀の大発明をした
making the invention of the century.
世界が平和になりますようにと
I genuinely and from the heart
本気で心から願った
wished for world peace.
だが 発明は兵器利用されて
But my invention was used as a weapon,
残酷な血の雨が降った
and a cruel rain of blood fell.
ああ またダメでした
Ah, I failed again—
転生しよう
time to reincarnate.
才能がないからチェンジ
No talent? Change.
またリセット
Reset again.
頭悪いからチェンジ
Stupid? Change.
またリセット
Reset again.
人生の攻略法 幸福の必勝法
The walkthrough of life, the winning formula for happiness—
境目ないね 「自分」が消えちゃいそうだな
there's no boundary, my "self" seems like it's disappearing.
流れてく 時の中でも
Flowing through the passage of time,
気だるさがほら ググル廻って
sluggishness goes spinning around and round.
私から 離れる心も見えないわ
I can't even see my heart drifting away from me—
そう知らない
I don't even know that.
自分から 動くこともなく
Without even moving on my own,
時の狭間に 流され続けて
I continue to be swept away in the gaps of time.
知らないわ 周りのことなど
I don't know anything about those around me;
私は私それだけ
I am just myself, nothing more.
夢見ている 何も見てない
Dreaming, yet seeing nothing at all,
語るも無駄な 自分の言葉
my own words are useless to speak.
悲しむなんて 疲れるだけよ
Grief is just exhausting,
何も感じず 過ごせばいいの
it's fine to spend days feeling nothing.
戸惑う言葉 与えられても
Even if given words of bewilderment,
自分の心だけ上の空
my heart is spaced out.
もし私から 動くのならば
If I were to move on my own,
すべて変えるのならば 黒にする
if I were to change everything, I'd make it black.
こんな自分に 未来はあるの
Does a future exist for someone like me?
こんな世界に 私はいるの
Do I even belong in a world like this?
今 切ないの 今 悲しいの
Right now I feel so poignant, right now I feel so sad,
自分のことも 解からないまま
still unable to even understand myself.
歩くことさえ 疲れるだけよ
Even just walking is simply exhausting;
人のことなど 知りもしないわ
I don't even care to know about others.
こんな私も 変えられるのならば
If even someone like me can change,
もし変えられるのならば 白になる
if I can change, I'll become white.
流れてく 時の中でも
Flowing through the passage of time,
気だるさがほら ググル廻って
sluggishness goes spinning around and round.
私から 離れる心も見えないわ
I can't even see my heart drifting away from me—
そう知らない
I don't even know that.
自分から 動くこともなく
Without even moving on my own,
時の狭間に 流され続けて
I continue to be swept away in the gaps of time.
知らないわ 周りのことなど
I don't know anything about those around me;
私は私それだけ
I am just myself, nothing more.
夢見ている 何も見てない
Dreaming, yet seeing nothing at all,
語るも無駄な 自分の言葉
my own words are useless to speak.
悲しむなんて 疲れるだけよ
Grief is just exhausting,
何も感じず 過ごせばいいの
it's fine to spend days feeling nothing.
戸惑う言葉 与えられても
Even if given words of bewilderment,
自分の心だけ上の空
my heart is spaced out.
もし私から 動くのならば
If I were to move on my own,
すべて変えるのならば 黒にする
if I were to change everything, I'd make it black.
こんな自分に 未来はあるの
Does a future exist for someone like me?
こんな世界に 私はいるの
Do I even belong in a world like this?
今 切ないの 今 悲しいの
Right now I feel so poignant, right now I feel so sad,
自分のことも 解からないまま
still unable to even understand myself.
歩くことさえ 疲れるだけよ
Even just walking is simply exhausting;
人のことなど 知りもしないわ
I don't even care to know about others.
こんな私も 変えられるのならば
If even someone like me can change,
もし変えられるのならば 白になる
if I can change, I'll become white.
流れてく 時の中でも
Flowing through the passage of time,
気だるさがほら ググル廻って
sluggishness goes spinning around and round.
私から 離れる心も見えないわ
I can't even see my heart drifting away from me—
そう知らない
I don't even know that.
自分から 動くこともなく
Without even moving on my own,
時の狭間に 流され続けて
I continue to be swept away in the gaps of time.
知らないわ 周りのことなど
I don't know anything about those around me;
私は私それだけ
I am just myself, nothing more.
夢見ている 何も見てない
Dreaming, yet seeing nothing at all,
語るも無駄な 自分の言葉
my own words are useless to speak.
悲しむなんて 疲れるだけよ
Grief is just exhausting,
何も感じず 過ごせばいいの
it's fine to spend days feeling nothing.
戸惑う言葉 与えられても
Even if given words of bewilderment,
自分の心だけ上の空
my heart is spaced out.
流れ行く時の中でも
Even in the midst of flowing time,
気だるさがほらググル廻って
languidness is spinning around and around,
私から離れる心も
even the heart leaving me
見えないわ そう知らない
can't be seen, that's right, I don't know.
自分から動くこともなく
I can't even get myself to move,
時の隙間に流れ続いて
flowing continuously down the cracks of time.
知らないわ周りのことなど
I don't know anything about what's around me,
私は私 それだけ
I'm just me and no more.
夢見てる？ 何も見てない？
Am I dreaming? Or seeing nothing?
語るも無駄な自分の言葉
My words are useless even if I speak.
悲しむなんて疲れるだけよ
I'm just tired of being sad,
何も感じず過ごせばいいの
I should go on without feeling anything.
戸惑う言葉与えられても
Even if you give me words I'm at a loss for,
自分の心ただ上の空
my heart just won't pay attention.
もし私から動くのならば
If I move myself away,
すべて変えるのならば黒にする
if I change everything, I'll turn it all black.
こんな自分に未来はあるの？
Is there a future for someone like me?
こんな世界に私はいるの？
Will I exist in a world like this?
今切ないの？ 今悲しいの？
Is this painful? Is it sad?
自分のこともわからないまま
Not even knowing myself,
歩くことさえ疲れるだけよ
I'm just tired even of walking.
人のことなど知りもしないわ
I don't even understand people,
こんな私も変われるのなら
if someone like me can change.
もし変われるのなら白になる
If I can change, will I turn white?
流れ行く時の中でも
Even in the midst of flowing time,
気だるさがほらググル廻って
languidness is spinning around and around,
私から離れる心も
even the heart leaving me
見えないわ そう知らない
can't be seen, that's right, I don't know.
自分から動くこともなく
I can't even get myself to move,
時の隙間に流れ続いて
flowing continuously down the cracks of time.
知らないわ周りのことなど
I don't know anything about what's around me,
私は私 それだけ
I'm just me and no more.
夢見てる？ 何も見てない？
Am I dreaming? Or seeing nothing?
語るも無駄な自分の言葉
My words are useless even if I speak.
悲しむなんて疲れるだけよ
I'm just tired of being sad,
何も感じず過ごせばいいの
I should go on without feeling anything.
戸惑う言葉与えられても
Even if you give me words I'm at a loss for,
自分の心ただ上の空
my heart just won't pay attention.
もし私から動くのならば
If I move myself away,
すべて変えるのならば黒にする
if I change everything, I'll turn it all black.
動くのならば動くのならば
If I move, if I move,
すべて壊すわすべて壊すわ
everything will break, everything will break.
悲しむならば悲しむならば
If I'm sad, if I'm sad,
私の心白く変われる？
will my heart be able to turn white?
貴方のことも私のことも
Still know nothing about you, about me,
全てのこともまだ知らないの
about anything at all.
いつか君が瞳に灯す愛の光が
Someday the light of love that you will kindle in your eyes
時を超えて 滅び急ぐ世界の夢を
will transcend time and break one of the fleeting dreams
確実に一つ壊そう
rushing toward destruction.
躊躇いを飲み干して 君が望むモノは何?
Casting aside hesitation, what is it that you desire?
こんな欲深い憧れの行方に 僅かな明日はあるの?
In this deep longing, is there a fleeting tomorrow?
子どもの頃夢に見てた 古の魔法のように
Like the ancient magic that I saw in my childhood dreams,
闇さえ砕く力で 微笑む君に会いたい
I want to meet you, smiling with the power to crush darkness.
怯えるこの手の中には 手折られた花の勇気
In these trembling hands lies the courage of fallen flowers;
想いだけが頼る全て 光を呼び覚ます 願い
all that relies on memory awakens the light—my wish.
いつか君も誰かの為に 強い力を望むのだろう
Someday, you too will seek strong power for someone else.
愛が胸を捉えた夜に 未知の言葉が生まれて来る
On a night when love captures your heart, new words are born.
迷わずに行けるなら 心が砕けてもいいわ
If you can go without hesitation, even if your heart breaks,
いつも目の前の悲しみに 立ち向う為の 呪文が欲しい
I want a spell to face the sorrow always before my eyes.
君はまだ夢見る記憶 私は眠らない明日
You still dream of memories; I face a sleepless tomorrow.
二人が出逢う奇跡を 勝ち取る為に進むの
We will advance to claim the miracle of our meeting.
怯えるこの手の中には 手折られた花の刃
In these trembling hands lies the blade of fallen flowers;
想いだけが生きる全て 心に振りかざす 願い
all that lives on memory I raise in my heart—my wish.
いつか君も 誰かのために
Someday you too, for someone's sake,
強い力を 望むのだろう
will you desire strong power?
愛が胸を 捉えた夜に 見知らぬ言葉が 生まれてくる
On a night when love captures your heart, unknown words are born.
迷わずに ゆけるなら 心が 砕けてもいいわ
If you can go without hesitation, even if your heart breaks,
いつも 目の前の 悲しみに 立ち向かう ための 呪文が 欲しい
I want a spell to face the sorrow always before my eyes.
君はまだ夢見る記憶 私は眠らない明日
You still dream of memories; I face a sleepless tomorrow.
二人が出逢う奇跡を 勝ち取るために 進むの
To claim the miracle of our meeting, we advance.
怯えるこの手の中には 手折られた花の 刃
In these trembling hands lies the blade of fallen flowers...
想いだけが生きる全て 心に 繰りかざす 願い
All that lives on memory I raise in my heart—my wish.
囚われた太陽の輝く
The radiance of the captured sun
不思議の国の本が好きだった頃
Back when I loved books about Wonderland,
願いはきっと叶うと 教えるおとぎ話を信じた
I believed in fairy tales that taught wishes would surely come true.
光と影の中
Amidst the light and shadow...
静かに咲き乱れていた イニシエの魔法を優しく
The ancient magic that quietly bloomed in disorder
世界を変える
gently changes the world.
力がその手にあると ささやく終わらない夢を見よう
When power is in your hands, let's see an endless dream whispered to us.
君と行く時の中で 思いだけが生きる全ての命を作るのは願い
Within the time traveling with you, it is wishes that create every life where only feelings live.
わあ！あきちゃん！お誕生日おめでとう！
Wow! Aki-chan! Happy birthday!
ありがとう！イエーイ！
Thank you! Yay!
今日は来てくれてありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for coming today.
こちらこそですよ、ありがとう！呼んでくれてありがとう！
Likewise, thank you! Thanks for inviting us!
実はね、2人を呼んだのにはちょっと理由があって。おっ、なんだなんだ？
Actually, there's a reason why I invited you two. Oh, what is it?
前にアキロゼの4周年の時に3人でハラミちゃんさんの曲出させてもらったんだよね。やりましたね！
Back at my 4th anniversary, the three of us released a Harami-chan song. We did!
めちゃよかったやつね！そう！ハーモニーがね！
That was such a great one! Yeah, the harmonies!
もうね、みおちゃんの歌も大好きだし、あさおの歌も大好きだし、もうね忘れられないの。
I love Mio-chan's singing, and Asa's singing too, I just can't forget it.
忘れない！忘れる！分かる！分かる！
I won't forget! I'll forget! I get it! Exactly!
だからもう1回ライブステージで3人で歌いたくて、今日は来てもらいました！嬉しい！ありがとう！ありがとう！
So I wanted us to sing it on a live stage once more, so I had you come today! So happy! Thank you!
だから、今後はこれを機にまたなんか3人で歌ったりとか、なんかそういうの挑戦できたらめっちゃ嬉しいね。
So from now on, I'd be so happy if we could take on challenges like singing together as a trio again.
いいですね！ハーモニーを重ねていきましょうよ。ええ、いいの？
That sounds great! Let's build up our harmonies. Oh, really?
えーユニット名とか欲しいな。え、なんだろう？
I'd love a unit name. Eh, what could it be?
なんか世界を目指せるぐらいの、世界規模のコンサートをしようよ。世界に届く我らが何かをね、したいということで。
Let's do a world-scale concert aiming for the global stage. We want to do something that reaches the world.
3人でライブとか、なんかアコースティックとか、なんかオーケストラライブとか、え、良くないですか？
A live show with the three of us, acoustic, or an orchestra live, wouldn't that be amazing?
ね、我らならできるかもしれない！おねがいします！お願いしますよ。
We might actually be able to pull it off! Please! We're counting on it.
あれ？これはいったいなんですか？
Huh? What in the world is this?
もしかして、このライブでみんなからの、なんかいいパワーで、なんかいいパワー来てる？イチアルじゃんそれ！
Could it be, from this live, everyone's great power... Is some good power coming? That's Ichial!
なんだよそのパワー！こちらがなんと、完成しました！なんだそれ！
What kind of power is that?! This has somehow been completed! What is that?!
実は、この後アキロゼの新曲がでます！わあ！出たー！
Actually, after this, a new song by Aki Rosenthal will be released! Wow! It's out!
こちら、今回のあのライブの、まあテーマというか、壮大なテーマがあるんですけれども、そちらの詰まったような楽曲になっています。
This song has a grand theme, sort of the theme of this live, and it's packed into this track.
そしてライブ終わりの日付が変わる時にリリースしますので、ぜひ買って、聞いてください！はーい！
And it will be released as the date changes after the live, so please buy and listen to it! Yay!
じゃあ、次の曲に行きますか？次の曲？新曲のお披露目？え、なんだって？しちゃいます！
Shall we move on to the next song? The next song? Revealing the new song? Eh, what? We're doing it!
もう新曲の、え、今からってこと？今から頑張ります！最後まで見逃せないですね。
The new song, right now? We'll do our best from now on! You won't want to miss a single moment.
お願いします！じゃあ、あきちゃん頑張ってね！ありがとう！頑張る！頑張ろう！
Please do! Well then, Aki-chan, do your best! Thank you! I'll do my best! Let's do our best!
迷い込む言葉の裏目に
Scattering words astray on the flip side,
散らばせた
scattered about.
1ミリ狂うのスパイス
A one-millimeter misaligned spice,
立ちまち華麗に
instantly and brilliantly
指先で彩る
adorning with fingertips.
本日のダイス
Today's dice.
あたり見てた？挙動不審じゃ
Were you watching? That's suspicious,
生き残れないでしょ
you won't survive, right?
率直にいって
Frankly speaking,
全部が欲しいの
I want everything.
一勝勝ちにオールイン
All-in for a single victory.
どうなっちゃってもいいじゃん
Whatever happens is fine,
限界なんてないじゃん
there are no limits, right?
翻弄して弄ばれてぞくぞく
Toyed with and toying around, thrilling,
喰らっちゃっても本望でしょ
even if I get devoured, that's what I want,
最低だって足る足りるでしょ
even at the worst, it's more than enough,
見透かして見透かされてヤリニ終わりは無い
seeing through and being seen through, play has no end,
高鳴るこの全てノンフィクション
this throbbing reality is non-fiction.
たしなみもハズゲもたまには飲みすぎて
Manners and taboos, sometimes drinking too much,
一回休み
lose a turn.
周りもそうすぐ思わぬうたかたねで
Everyone too, so fleeting and unexpected,
二回休み
lose two turns.
切れる頭と勘だけじゃ手に入らないもの
What you can't get with just a sharp mind and intuition,
そこでいて見逃せるならいい
if you stay there and can let it go, fine,
命懸けて楽しめばいいや
just risk your life and enjoy it to the fullest!
先行きは案外近いな この通り
The future is surprisingly close, just like this.
命がけ高がモノポリー
Risking your life, it's a high-stakes Monopoly.
それも良し決める想いに恋い焦がれ私は強い
That's fine too, yearning for the feelings you decide on, I am strong.
どうなっちゃってもいいじゃん
Whatever happens is fine,
限界なんてないじゃん
there are no limits, right?
翻弄して弄ばれてぞくぞく
Toyed with and toying around, thrilling,
喰らっちゃっても本望でしょ
even if I get devoured, that's what I want,
最低だって足る足りるでしょ
even at the worst, it's more than enough,
見透かして見透かされてヤリニ終わりは無い
seeing through and being seen through, play has no end,
高鳴るこの全てノンフィクション
this throbbing reality is non-fiction.
堕ちても昇ってもノンフィクション
Whether falling or rising, it's non-fiction.
中川に浮かぶ 夕日をめがけて 小石を蹴ったら 靴まで飛んで
Aiming at the setting sun floating on the Nakagawa, if I kicked a pebble, even my shoe flew off.
ジョギングしていた 大工の頭領に
The carpenter boss who was jogging
ガキのまんまだと 笑われたのさ
laughed at me, saying I'm still just a kid.
どこかに元気を 落っことしとっても 葛飾亀有 あくびをひとつ
Even if you drop your energy somewhere, Katsushika Kameari, just one yawn,
変わらない町並みが 妙にやさしいよ
the unchanged streets are strangely gentle.
中央広場で 子供の手を引く 太ったあの娘は 初恋の彼女
In the central plaza holding a child's hand, that plump girl is my first love.
ゴンパチ池で 渡したラブレター 今も持っていると からかわれたよ
At Gonpachi pond I handed her a love letter, they teased me that I still have it.
何にもいいこと なかったけれど 葛飾水元 流れる雲と
Even though nothing good happened, with the clouds flowing over Katsushika Mizumoto,
ラプソディ口ずさみ 少し歩こうか
humming a rhapsody, shall I walk a little?
カラスが鳴くから もう日が暮れるね
Because crows caw, the sun is setting,
焼鳥ほうばり ビール飲もうか
let's munch yakitori and drink beer.
トンガリ帽子の 取水塔から
From the pointed hat water tower
帝釈天へと 夕日が落ちる
the setting sun falls toward Taishakuten.
明日もこうして 終わるんだね
Tomorrow too it will end like this,
葛飾柴又 惜しんでだって泣いて気付いた 馬鹿な俺だから
Katsushika Shibamata, realizing through tears what I missed, because I'm a fool.
どこかに元気を 落っことしとっても 葛飾亀有 あくびをひとつ
Even if you drop your energy somewhere, Katsushika Kameari, just one yawn,
変わらない町並みが 妙にやさしいよ
the unchanged streets are strangely gentle.
どこかに元気を 落っことしとっても 葛飾亀有 あくびをひとつ
Even if you drop your energy somewhere, Katsushika Kameari, just one yawn,
変わらない町並みが 妙にやさしいよ
the unchanged streets are strangely gentle.
中川に浮かぶ夕日をめがけて
Aiming for the sunset floating on the Nakagawa River,
小石を蹴ったら靴まで飛んで
When I kicked a pebble, my shoe went flying too.
内緒だけどあたし幸せだった
It's a secret, but I was happy.
隠して出逢った 馬鹿な骨だから
Because we're foolish souls who met in secret.
どこかに元気を 落っこことしても
Even if I drop my energy somewhere along the way,
葛飾亀有 あくびをひとつ
In Katsushika Kameari, let out a yawn,
変わらない町並みが 妙にやさしいよ
The unchanging townscape is strangely gentle.
中央広場で 子供の手を引く
At the central plaza, leading a child by the hand,
太ったあの娘は 初恋の人
That plump girl is my first love.
ゴンパチ池で 渡したラブレター
The love letter I handed over at Gonpachi Pond,
今も持っていると からかわれたよ
Teased that I still have it.
アキロゼ生誕祭2026をご覧の皆さん いかがでしたでしょうか？
To everyone watching the Aki Rosenthal Birthday Festival 2026, how was it?
さて、ここからは大切なお知らせがあるので最後までしっかり聞いていってね！
Now, I have some important announcements, so make sure to listen carefully to the end!
まずは お知らせ1つ目！
First, announcement number one!
アキロゼ全体の2026誕生日グッズ発売です！
The release of Aki Rosenthal's 2026 Birthday Goods!
今回はライブの世界観をぎゅっと楽しんでもらえるグッズを頑張って製作いたしました！
This time, we worked hard to create goods that let you fully enjoy the worldview of the live stream!
なので今回のライブがよかったなって思った方は是非応援で購入していただけるのもすごく嬉しいです！
So if you thought this live was great, I'd be so happy if you supported me by purchasing them!
それではまず1つ目のグッズ！Life is GAME ラバーマット！
First up, goods number one! Life is GAME rubber mat!
今回のイラストはLAM先生に描き下ろしていただきました！素敵なイラストありがとうございます！
This time's illustration was drawn by LAM-sensei! Thank you so much for the wonderful illustration!
今回のライブの世界観をイメージしたイラストになっています！めちゃくちゃセクシーで色っぽいけどかっこいいようなアキロゼになっています！
It's an illustration imagining the world of this live! It shows Aki Rosenthal being super sexy and alluring, yet cool!
ラバーマットでおもいっそ楽しんでください！ちなみにサイズはカードゲームにぴったり！この意味分かるよね？
Please enjoy it to the fullest with the rubber mat! By the way, the size is perfect for card games! You know what that means, right?
2つ目のグッズが 運命の5枚 タロット風アクリルスタンドセット！
The second goods set is the "Five Fates Tarot-Style Acrylic Stand Set"!
3つ目のグッズは アキロゼのトランプ！作っちゃいました！こちらは実際に遊んでいただけるトランプなのでたくさん予備も買ったほうがいいんじゃないかなと思います！
The third goods item is Aki Rosenthal's playing cards! We actually made them! Since these are actual playable cards, I think you should buy plenty of spares!
続いてはこちら！アキロゼのカードケース！このケースはもちろんトランプなど小物を入れても大丈夫です！ぜひおうちや持ち歩きに使ってね！
Next is this! Aki Rosenthal's card case! Of course, you can put playing cards and other small items in this case too! Please use it at home or when you're out and about!
そして ボイスの紹介です！今回もASMRボイスを特別に発売！
And now, introducing the voice tracks! We're also specially releasing ASMR voice tracks this time!
これらのグッズすべてがつまったフルセット購入にはなんと特典もついております！
For those who purchase the full set containing all these goods, there is even a special bonus included!
大事な発売時間はこの後21時30分！21時30分にショップオープンです！
The important release time is coming up at 21:30! The shop opens at 21:30!
続きまして お知らせ2つ目！このあと21時45分からメンバー限定のアフターライブを行います！
Moving on to announcement number two! Starting at 21:45, we will hold a member-only after-party live!
あとライブも見れちゃうと思うので ぜひそのあたりもみてみてね
You'll be able to watch the after-live too, so be sure to check that out as well!
ちなみに今回のサムネイルイラストはメンバー限定で壁紙としてプレゼント予定です お楽しみに！
By the way, the thumbnail illustration for this time is planned to be gifted as wallpaper exclusively for members. Look forward to it!
そしてお知らせ3つめ！本日の生誕祭ライブの後もお楽しみはまだまだ続きます！
And announcement number three! The fun continues even after today's birthday live!
なんとホロアースにて特別企画 アキ・ローゼンタール生誕祭アンコール in ホロアースを開催します！
We will hold a special project in Holoearth: Aki Rosenthal's Birthday Encore in Holoearth!
今回初披露した新曲「モノポリー」をホロアースで歌っちゃいます！いろんな角度からアキローゼのパフォーマンスや演出をじっくりと見てみてくださいね。
We'll be singing the newly unveiled song 'Monopoly' in Holoearth! Be sure to take a close look at AkiRose's performances and staging from various angles.
さらにホロアースだけのMCパートもたっぷりあるので、ぜひぜひ会いに来てください！
There will also be plenty of MC parts unique to Holoearth, so please come meet us!
開催日は3月13日！3月13日です！詳細はホロアース公式Xをチェックしてね。
The date is March 13th! March 13th! Check the official Holoearth X for details.
そして最後のお知らせが
And the final announcement is...
魅惑のコトバの裏面に忍ばせた 1mgのスパイシー
A 1mg of spice hidden behind seductive words
たちまち華麗な指先で彩る 本日のダイス
Instantly coloring with gorgeous fingertips today's dice
傍見見て妥協してちゃ生き残れないでしょう 正直言って全てが欲しい！
If you watch from the side and compromise, you won't survive, right? Honestly, I want everything!
一人勝負にオールイン どうなっちたっていいじゃない
All-in on a solo game, it doesn't matter how it turns out
限界なんてないじゃない 翻弄して翻弄されてゾ・ク・ゾ・ク
There's no limit, right? Toyed with and toying around, thrilling
喰らっちたって本望でしょ
Even if I get devoured, it's what I wish for
また後日ライブ配信で新曲モノポリーだったり今回のライブに触れた後日談などを語ったり一緒に見たりなどしたいなと思ってるので
I'm thinking of talking about behind-the-scenes stories touching on the new song Monopoly or this live in a future live stream, and watching it together,
ぜひチャンネル登録高評価ポチッ通知もオンにしてた人は今ポチッとしてね絶対絶対また会いに来てね！
so please subscribe, like, and turn on notifications if you haven't yet, and hit it now! Absolutely, absolutely come meet me again!
それでは運命は時に残酷 あなたが選びたくて選んだものではないかもしれない
Well then... Fate is sometimes cruel. It might not be something you chose because you wanted to.
だけどいつでもあなたの人生はあなたのもの
However, your life is always your own.
人生は一度きり やり直しの利かないこのゲーム あなたはどうお楽しむ？
Life is a once-in-a-lifetime game with no do-overs. How will you enjoy it?